Vivian G. Brown

Berkeley, CA • vivian.brown@gmail.com
Portfolio: vivianbrown.appspot.com • GitHub: github.com/vbrown608

SUMMARY

Designed and built a sophisticated web application in Python, JavaScript/JQuery, HTML5 and CSS3. Wrote and published widely-read research on enterprise Agile software development and user experience delivery. Conducted research using applied predictive analysis and machine learning techniques on bioacoustic data.

EDUCATION

Pomona College, Claremont, CA 2007-2011 Bachelor of Arts in Cognitive Science Minor in Computer Science Cum Laude, GPA 3.81/4.00 Undergraduate thesis in machine translation

- Identified features of simple sentences based on models of linguistic complexity
- Working in Java, re-ranked the output of a probabilistic phrase-based translation model using a support vector machine re-ranker to improve machine translation

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IT Researcher/Analyst Forrester Research (October 2012-present)

- Wrote syndicated research on Agile software development, requirements definition, cloud platforms, and predictive analytics tools for senior application development leaders in Fortune 500 IT organizations
- Automated team processes in Excel (Visual Basic) and Google Docs (JavaScript/Google App Script) including integration with Salesforce via OAuth2
- Worked on 3,000+ respondent surveys including survey design, data cuts and analysis, and creation of figures for publication in Adobe Illustrator
- Awarded "Best Research Award" Q3 2012 and "Most Courageous Research Award" Q3 2013
- Promoted to Senior Research Associate after twelve months, then promoted to Researcher after five months

Machine Learning Research Assistant to Dr. Xiaoli Fern, Oregon State University (Summer 2010)

- Working in C++, applied predictive analysis and machine learning techniques to bioacoustic data
- Contributed to a shared code base on a five-person team
- Collected, read, and summarized research on bioacoustic data analysis with focus on random forest algorithm
- Summarized results in a written report and presented at the Grace Hopper Conference for Women in Computing

Webmaster Department of Cognitive Science and Linguistics, Pomona College (2010-2011)

- Worked with faculty and staff to update the content and design of department website
- Using HTML and CSS, updated navigation system, restructured faculty profiles, and posted regular updates

Computer Science Teaching Assistant Department of Computer Science, Pomona College (2010-2011)

- TA for "Fundamentals of Computer Science" and "Data Structures" courses
- Facilitated programming labs and held weekly office hours to assist with assignments in Java, C++, and SML

PROJECTS

MetaTicTacToe metatictactoe.appspot.com - browser-based strategy game

Backend: Python on Google App Engine, GQL, Channel API, webapp2 framework, Jinja2 templating Frontend: JavaScript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Adversarial search: negamax algorithm with alpha-beta pruning

Version controlled in Git/GitHub

I also know a little: MySQL, Ruby on Rails, AJAX, Google Maps JavaScript API v3, D3.js